Jolon Behrent

M: 027 966 5738

E: jolon.behrent@gmail.com
L: linkedin.com/in/jolonb

I am an ambitious electronic engineer with professional experience in software development. I am well acquainted with electronic design and analysis, and I have skills in a range of programming languages. Working on team projects has given me the expertise necessary to work successfully in a team. I have proven myself to be a self-motivated and accomplished individual through my success in previous jobs and at university.

I sometimes spend my spare time experimenting with electronics and programming to learn more and put my skills to use. I enjoy being challenged, so I believe a job that interests me and gives me an opportunity to learn new things will be great for my development as an engineer and will push me to my full potential.



Achievements

Dean's List 2017, 2018, and 2019

For excellent grades in my past three years of study, I have been awarded places on the Faculty of Engineering Dean's List at Victoria University.

NCEA Excellence Endorsements

I was awarded Excellence Endorsements in NCEA Levels 1, 2, and 3.

The Kennedy Memorial Medal for Diligence

This was awarded to one of the top academic students in year 13 at St. Patrick's College.

Outstanding Service in the College Award

This was awarded to a small group of year 13 students at St. Patrick's College, who had made a significant contribution to the college through leadership and other volunteer roles.

Skills

Electronics

Through courses at university and by doing personal projects I have developed my skills in electronics. I have hands-on experience with microcontroller programming, digital logic, and circuit design/testing. I have written VHDL code for FPGAs and I have experience with software including LTspice, Altium, and KiCad.

Programming

I have experience working with Java through university courses, writing small programs in my spare time, and from my internship at Tait Communications. I have used MATLAB for many things from performing statistical analysis to designing control systems. I am proficient in Python and C/C++, both of which I have studied and had an opportunity to use during my internship at Aviat Networks and in personal projects.

Language	Length of Time	Context
Java	3 years	University, Work
Python	3 years	University, Work
C/C++	2 years	University, Work
MATLAB	3 years	University

Teamwork

I work well in teams and I have experience working in groups of various sizes. I have worked in a team on several occasions as an intern and at university. I am familiar with Agile methodologies after using them during my internship at Aviat Networks and in projects at university.

Self-Motivated

I am constantly pushing myself to learn new things and to complete work on time. This is reflected in my success at university as I always work to complete things to a high standard. I also do personal projects in my own time as a way of expanding my knowledge and gaining a better understanding of a topic.

Education

University

Victoria University of Wellington Bachelor of Engineering (Hons) Electronic and Computer Systems Engineering 2017 – present Average Grade: A

College

Saint Patrick's College, Silverstream 2012 – 2016

Personal Interests

- Experimenting with electronics
- Watching bad movies
- Playing Dungeons and Dragons

Referees

Available on request

Work Experience

Embedded Software Developer/Tester

Aviat Networks, Lower Hutt

18th November 2019 – 21st February 2020

This 12-week internship involved developing C/C++ code for an embedded radio system. In addition to this, I also performed manual testing and developed automated test scripts in Python. This position had me working in an Agile team which greatly improved my ability to work cooperatively in a professional environment.

Junior Design Engineer

Tait Communications, Christchurch 19th November 2018 – 8th February 2019

This 10-week internship had me writing and developing a tool in Java which was designed to calculate intermodulation distortion in radio systems. This involved developing an algorithm to find intermodulation as well as creating a user interface for the tool. The internship allowed me to learn more about radio systems and improve my programming skills.

University Tutor

Victoria University of Wellington

Trimester 1, 2018; Trimester 1/2, 2019; Trimester 1/2 2020

For these roles, I have worked in the university labs assisting students in completing lab work and assignments. This role helped me improve my time management and problem-solving skills.

Retail Assistant

Bin Inn Petone

10th September 2017 – 11th November 2018

This role involves me working in a grocery store as a checkout operator. It has helped me develop teamwork and interpersonal skills.